&gt；&gt；[音乐]
&gt;&gt; [MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：我确实说过RxJS非常标准化，它是
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: I did say that RxJS is pretty well standardized it's
A这真是个好主意。
a it's a really good idea.
这可能是一种很好的感觉，我们最终会得到什么或者
It's probably a pretty good sense of what we're going to end up with or
非常接近的东西。
something very close to it.
如果我们在JavaScript中获得了观察值。
If we get observables in JavaScript.
老实说，我已经尝试了很多次来学习RxJS。
I've tried a number of times to learn RxJS honestly I have.
我从来没有足够的时间
I've never had enough time
为了通过所有这些文档，我所经历过的培训课程。
to get through all of that documentation the training courses I've gone through.
这需要很大的努力，相对而言，
It takes a lot of effort and, comparatively speaking,
如果我试图分析我在程序中所做的基于异步事件的编码，
if I try to analyze the asynchronous event based coding that I do in my programs,
实际上，有一小部分事情是我真正在共同的基础上做的。
there's actually kind of a small subset of things that I really do on a common basis.
所以我突然想到，如果我已经非常熟悉使用异步
So it occurred to me that if I'm already pretty familiar with using asynquence for
我的发电机和我的承诺
my generators and my promises,
为什么不具有异步的反应式编程能力。
why not have reactive programming capabilities with an asynquence.
这实际上非常适合，因为我已经在处理序列了。
That actually fits pretty well ,because I'm already dealing with sequences.
这是我的抽象，所以我需要做的就是能够做出可重复的序列。
That's my abstraction, so all I need to do is be able to make repeatable sequences.
然后它恰好与已经创建和创建的相同的抽象相适应
And then it fits right in with the same abstractions that have already created and
我所拥有的所有相同的方法和实用程序，
all the same methods and utilities that I've got,
他们也都在做反应。
they all work on reactive as well.
所以我所做的就是将反应序列添加到文库中。
So what I did was add reactive sequences to the library.
为了我们的目的，而不是我试图让你陷入学习
For our purposes, rather than me trying to get you bogged down into learning all
RxJS的复杂性，我将向你们展示非常有效的反应序列，
the complexities of RxJS, I'm gonna show you reactive sequences which work very,
非常类似于RxJS观测值。
very similarly to the RxJS observables.
我实际上要向你展示，你可以透明地在两者之间穿梭。
And I'm actually gonna show you that you can transparently go between the two.
所以，你可以采取反应序列，使RxJS可观察到，
So, you can take in a reactive sequence and make an RxJS observable and
如果需要的话，反之亦然。
vice versa if you need to.
但这就像，就像五个或
But this is just like, it's like the five or
你需要在一个很小的实现中放入六个最常见的方法。
six most common ones you need put down and inside of a tiny little implementation.
所以不需要带一个20万的图书馆，
So instead of having to bring in a 200k library,
你只需花3k的异步时间就能得到这个。
you get this for like 3k in asynquence.
所以这就是它想要做的所有事情
So that's really all it is trying to make it a little
让你的大脑更容易缠绕。
little easier to wrap your brain around.
所以我可以创建一个类似于fromEvent的实用程序，它看起来与
So I can make a utility like fromEvent which looks exactly like the one
由采用Done元素的Observables提供，它采用事件名称并
provided by the observables that takes an done element takes an event name and
它连接和
it attaches and
这里我使用JQuery只是为了节省幻灯片上的空间，当然我们不使用JQuery。
here I'm using JQuery just to save room on the slides of course we don't use JQuery.
[咳嗽]所以从通风口实用程序是我如何使一个可观察的和
[COUGH] So from a vent utility is how I make an observable and
你看，我是在第8行做的。
you see I do that on line 8.
现在我要叫我的，我用反应序列而不是可观察的
Now I'm gonna call mine I use the term reactive sequence instead of observable
我是故意的。
I did that on purpose.
因为它不是可观察到的
Because it's not an observable
它与可观测的物体是同构的，它们可以来回移动。
it's isomorphic with observables they can go back and forth.
但它不是一个可观察到的，它是我自己的小东西，它是一个小得多的简单
But it's not an observable it's my own little thing it's a much smaller simpler
事情就是这样，而不是说它是可观察的，让人们抱怨
thing so rather than calling it an observable and having people complain
它所做的事情与我们的RxJS观测值并不完全相同。
that it doesn't do exactly the same thing that our RxJS observables do.
这是一个反应序列，但它显然非常相似。
It's a reactive sequence, but it's transparently very similar.
这样你就可以来回走了。
So you can go back and forth.
所以我把它叫做rsq，为了清楚起见，这是一个反应序列。
So I'm going to call it rsq, just to keep things clear, it's a reactive sequence.
然后你会注意到我就像我一样开始用链子把它脱下来
And then you'll notice I just start chaining off of it exactly like I do
任何其他的不同步。
any other asynquence.
使用过的.flations和.thens和.seqs。
Used .vals and .thens and .seqs.
我可以使用.runners，我可以使用提供给我的任何抽象
I can use .runners, I can use any of the abstractions provided to me
由异步文库直接脱离反应序列。
by the asynchronous library directly off of a reactive sequence.
在幕后，反应序列负责重复所有这些步骤
And under the covers the reactive sequence takes care of repeating all those steps
每次都有新的数据流过，所以
every time a new piece of data flows through, so
你不必担心整个重复的事情。
you don't have to worry about that whole repeating thing.
它知道如何一遍又一遍地重复这个链条。
It figures out how to repeat the chain over, and over, and over again.
你可以把反应序列想成序列模板。
You could sort of think about a reactive sequences like a sequence template.
您声明序列模板看起来像异步序列将重复，
You declare what the sequence template looks like an asynquence will repeat,
它将在每次需要时克隆并重复该模板。
it will clone and repeat that template every time it needs to.
所以这是一种非常轻量级的开始使用Observable的方法
So that's a pretty lightweight way of getting started playing with observables
你不需要什么大图书馆。
you don't need some big library.
你只需要获取你已经拥有的知识，
You just take knowledge that you already have,
一点点关于异步的知识，然后把它连接起来。
a little bit of a knowledge about asynquence, and hook it up.
主要的是，正如你在2号线上看到的那样，
And the main thing, as you can see up there on line 2,
我们创建反应序列的主要方式是ASQ.React。
the main way we create a reactive sequence is to say ASQ.react.
这给了我们一个函数，我称之为继续。
And that gives us a function, which I call proceed.
每次那个东西被调用，
And every time that thing is called,
无论您传递给它的是沿链向下泵送的数据。
whatever you pass to it is data that gets pumped down the chain.
这真的很简单。
It's really pretty straightforward.
我想指出From Event的另一种实现方式
I want to point out an alternate implementation of that from event
向你展示一种不同的思考反应序列的方式。
to show you a different way of thinking about a reactive sequence.
在这里，我通过只说ASQ.react.of来制作一个空的反应序列
Here, I make an empty reactive sequence by just saying ASQ.react.of
其中没有数据，这与RxJS使用的语法完全相同。
with no data in it that's exactly the same syntax as RxJS uses.
它们有一个.of方法，您可以不向其中传递任何内容或向其中传递数据，因此
They have a .of method that you can pass nothing into it or pass data into it so
完全一样。
it's exactly the same thing.
但是您注意到，我在第3行引用了一个push方法。
But you notice that I have a push method that I'm referencing on line 3.
因此您可以手动将数据泵入您的反应序列
So you can manually pump data into your reactive sequences
这就是我在这里做的。
which is what I'm doing here.
我正在使事件绑定手动抽出数据，它
I'm making the event binding manually pump data and it's
将完成与另一边的代码完全相同的事情，但它显示
gonna accomplish exactly the same thing as the code on the other side but it shows
反应序列是指如果你愿意，你可以将数据泵入其中的东西。
you the reactive sequences are things that you can pump data into if you want to.
实际上，我最终使用了相当多的东西。
I actually end up using that quite a bit.
这里有一个简单的例子。
So here's a quick example.
我在第1行创建了一个名为RSQ1的空序列，然后
I make an empty sequence up on line 1 called rsq1, and
我制作了另一个名为rsq2的文件，我在其中预置了一些数据，
I make another one called rsq2, which I preset some data in,
我预抽了三个数据，三个数字，1，2，3。
I pre-pumped some data in three pieces of data, three numbers, 1, 2, 3.
然后我给自己安排了一段时间。
And then I set myself up with an interval.
所以我打算
So I'm just going to,
每500毫秒向下推送一些更多的数据。
every 500 milliseconds push some more data down that stream.
每一条流，我都会往下推一些数字。
Each one of those streams, I'm gonna push some numbers down.
所以这些是从6和7行的10和11开始的，值10和
So those are starting out at 10 and 11 there on line 6 and 7, the values 10 and
11随着它们的增加。
11 as they increment.
在我的计划的其他地方，我将订阅这两个
Elsewhere in my program I'm going to subscribe to those two
观察到这两个反应序列。
observables those two reactive sequences.
第十行我订阅了RSQ1，然后打印出我在那里得到的任何内容
Line ten I subscribe to rsq1 and I print out whatever I'm getting there and
您会注意到，如果您在那里跟随流程，因为RSQ1没有任何数据
you notice if you follow the flow there because rsq1 didn't have any data
流中得到的第一个数据片段是值10。
the first piece of data gets down the stream is the value ten.
然后500毫秒后，它得到值12，然后是值14。
And then 500 milliseconds later, it gets the value 12, and then the value 14.
那么rsq2呢？它在流中已经有三个数据段了。
What about rsq2 it already had three pieces of data in the stream.
所以1，2和3马上就会出来，就像我们在第18行看到的那样。
So the 1, 2 and 3 are gonna come out right away as we see on line 18.
然后我们将开始每500毫秒获得值11，13，
And then we're gonna start every 500 milliseconds getting the values 11, 13,
15等等。
15 and so forth.
所以这些就是我们可以将数据注入其中的流
So these are just streams we can pump data into them and
在另一端获取数据，仅此而已。
get data out on the other end that's all.
这就是理解这里发生的一切。
That's all it takes to understand what's happening here.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：因为这些只是
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Because these are just
流，我们可以定义更高级别的操作，流操作。
streams, we can define higher level operations, the stream operations.
这可能是我要教你的最重要的事情
This is maybe the most important thing that I'm going to teach you about all of
反应式编程。
reactive programming.
这才是真正解锁反应式编程的魔力。
This is what really unlocks the magic of reactive programming.
如果您将它们视为流，我们可以定义某些操作
If you think about them as streams, we can define certain operations for
将流组合在一起。
composing streams together.
这里我有两个不同的流，我有一个rsq1和rsq2。
So here I have two different streams, I have an rsq1 and rsq2.
它们都来自不同的DOM事件。
They're both coming from different DOM events.
其中之一是点击按钮
One of them is clicks on a button and
其中之一是输入框中的按键，好吗？
one of them is key presses in an input box, okay?
我们可以单独订阅这些
We could individually subscribe to those and
当这些事件中的任何一个发生时，都会得到通知。
be notified when any one of those events happen.
但是如果我想听一种合成的事件流，告诉我
But what if I wanted to listen to a sort of synthetic event stream that told me
当这两件事同时发生的时候？
whenever those two things happened at exactly the same time?
我可以听一下.all操作员。
I could listen for the .all operator.
这是一个流运算符，它说我只会在rsq3上激发一个事件。
That's a stream operator that says I'm only gonna fire an event on rsq3.
每当我有来自所有输入流的事件时。
Whenever I have an event from all of my input streams.
所以如果按键是先发生的，我会等到按钮被点击，
So if the key press happens first, I'm gonna wait until I get the button click,
现在我有了这两个事件，我将把这两个事件放在一起
and now that I have these two events I'm gonna put those two together and
在rsq3流上激发它们。
fire them out on the rsq3 stream.
所以我创建了一个合成事件流
So I've created a synthetic event stream
基于两个较低级别流的组合。
based on the composition of two lower level streams.
这就是.all，顺便说一下，在RxJS术语中，.all被称为.zip，所以
That's .all, and by the way in RxJS terminology .all is called .zip so
在RxJS他们有一个拉链。
in RxJS they have a zip.
有一个别名，如果你喜欢RxJS术语，你可以在这里使用点zip，我只是，
There's an alias if you like the RxJS terms, you can use dot zip here, I just,
ZIP对我来说很奇怪，所以我用.all。
zip is weird to me so I used .all.
在RxJS中还有一个叫做Merge的，我把它叫做。Any，意思是，
And there's another one called merge in RxJS, which I called .any that says,
我有两个或更多的流入流
I've got two or more incoming streams and
我想在任何时候从他们那里得到任何东西都可以触发一个事件。
I want to fire an event any time I get anything from any of them.
所以只要我从任何一条流中找到一条就把他赶出去
So just fire him out as quick as soon as I get one from any stream fired it back out
顺流而下。
down the stream.
这被称为弧机会世界中的合并。
And that's called the merge in the arcs chance world.
如果你想回去看看，这是Rx弹珠。
Here's the Rx marbles if you want to go back and look.
所以zip是流操作的RxJS术语。
So zip is the RxJS terminology for that stream operation.
你可以看到一个从一条小溪中出来
And you can see that one comes out on one stream and
A一出现就来了另一个。
A comes in another as soon as A shows up.
在名为1A的输出流上激发一个事件，其中包含数据1A，并且
An event is fired on the output stream called 1 A with the data 1 A in it and
然后当2和B出现时，然后2B出去。
then when 2 and B show up then 2 B goes out.
C和D走到了一起，但我们仍在等待3和
C and D come together but we're still waiting on a 3 and
然后我们得到3C和4D。
then we get 3 C and 4 D.
所以向下的复合流有一个更高阶流
So that composite stream down there is a higher order stream to
定义为两个或多个输入流的组合。
defined as a composition of two or more input streams.
这是您可以学习的最强大的技术之一。
This is one of the most powerful techniques that you can learn.
了解如何对流经应用程序的数据进行建模或
Is understanding how to model the data that's flowing through your app or
操作，你的申请。
operation, your application.
作为一系列流操作
As a series of stream operations
如果不练习我所说的，它会感觉非常深奥
without practicing what I'm saying it's going to feel very esoteric and
我们对你来说是我理解的。
we are to you I understand that.
但我向你保证，如果你开始练习定向你的应用程序
But I promise you if you start practicing orienting your application around
异步事件并使用这些高阶流操作。
asynchronous events and using these higher order stream operations.
这就像生活中的另一组灯泡熄灭了。
It's like another set of light bulbs go off in life.
哇，我是怎么得到一切的？
Wow, how did I ever get all?
我怎么才能不使用它作为我的数据流建模方法呢？
How do I ever get around not using that as my way of modeling data flow?
所以人们对此非常兴奋
So it's right that people are super excited about this
反应式编程。
reactive programming thing.
它将彻底改变我们一直以来的一大堆糟糕的事情
It's gonna completely change a whole bunch of really crappy stuff that we've been
做了很长一段时间。
doing for a long time.
Freddy Mausers的其他工作坊喜欢Jeff的工作坊，非常棒的工作坊。
The other workshops from Freddy Mausers like Jeff's workshop, fantastic workshop.
都在观察点上。
It's all in on observables.
它一直都是可观察的，而且很棒。
It's all observables all the time and it's great.
Netflix正在使用它，微软正在使用它
Netflix is using it, Microsoft's using it,
每个人都很喜欢这个可观察的东西。
everybody's really in on this observables thing.
所以我认为我们应该给予它一些关注。
So I think we should we owe it some attention.
我们应该把注意力放在学习和看到这一点上。
We owe it our attention to kind of learn that and see that.
我认为如果承诺和生成器代表基线，那就是
I think if promises and generators represent the baseline, the thing that's
即将出现的是每个人都在使用的可观察到的东西。
right over the horizon is observables are gonna be what everybody is using.
这并不意味着承诺会消失，但是
It doesn't mean that promises are gonna go away but
这意味着，在我们的工具带中，观察表将成为一个非常强大的工具。
it means that observables are going to be a really powerful tool in our tool belt.